# Carine Todmia

# Senior Software Engineer

Maryland, USA | carinetodmia.com | github.com/ctodmia | ctodmia@gmail.com

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Senior Software Engineer | Capital One 2019 - Present Mclean, VA

Develops and manages the Virtual Card experience on capitalone.com

- Manages customer-facing features to consistently deliver mission-critical applications to over 13 million customers using Typescript, Angular, RXJS and NGRX
- Creates feature that integrate with 3rd party platform REST API such as Salesforce, Paypal and Google Pay
- Incorporates internationalization and accessibility using Ruby on Rails and custom CRM tool (Trestle) to improve site usability
- Leads technical architecture discussions and decisioning on feature delivery by providing documentation, prototypes, and testing plans for cross-platform teams
- Implements standardized features in shared components to increase platform adoption and improve accessibility experience for customers
- Routinely performs code reviews for best practices and production readiness
- Maintains automation testing using tools such as Jest, Jasmine, Cypress, Playwright and Selenium resulting in 99% code coverage

## Associate Software Engineer | Capital One 2017 - 2019 McLean, VA

Launched Eno Web Assistant Chrome extension at initial SXSW release to generate over 10,000 new users and eventually over \$1 billion in credit card spend

- Improved CI/CD to deploy Kubernetes clusters using Jenkins
- Experience implementing backend 2-factor authentication services
- Optimized SQL queries for improved performance and availability
- Designed and submitted relevant patents for Capital One products
- Mentored incoming software engineers in training
- Represented Capital One at national conference to support recruiting efforts
- Conducted technical interviews for senior engineers that resulted in hiring of 4 senior engineers

#### Lead Software Engineer | Ziploop 2016 - 2017 Orinda, CA

Digital wallet, OCR receipt processing, and rewards distribution platform

- Redesigned companies application to increase conversion rate by 20%
- Automated reward distribution and integration for Shopify users through
- RESTful API microservices
- Improved coding practices by refactoring legacy code, writing style guides for internal use, and participating in formal code reviews

## Founder/Software Engineer | C-Infinity Media 2015 - 2017 Los Angeles, CA

- Deployed web applications on Heroku and maintained hosting services for companies in order to persist online presence
- Leveraged designed tools such as Photoshop and Illustrator to create custom, high converting websites for small businesses
- Developed lead generation strategy for subscription based startup

#### Data Steward | Dell Software Group 2013 - 2014 Aliso Viejo, CA

- Used tools such as Salesforce, Oracle, and Siebel to managed large quantities of customer and prospect data
- Supported sales team by creating, standardizing, and appending account data to customers and prospects.

#### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Senior software engineer with 7+ years of experience designing and building responsive web applications in the financial industry. Advanced in JS Frameworks, with extensive knowledge of UX and user psychology. Notable achievements include developing and launching the Digital Card experience on capitalone.com and the Eno Web Assistant extension.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Javascript | Typescript | Angular | React, MongoDB | HTML5/CSS3 | Git | REST APIs | Node/Express | Redux/NGRX | Selenium, Cypress | Jest | Playwright | Webpack | Heroku | AWS | Ruby on Rails/Ruby | SQL | Photoshop | Illustrator | Java | Python | Kubernetes | Jenkins | Linux

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

### Team Collaboration Slack Bot - 2nd Place

Participated in company-wide hackathon to produce team collaboration Slack Bot application. Team won 2nd place out of 13 Teams.

# Machine Learning Data Collection Chrome Extension tool

Developed chrome extension that used ML to train models and detect credit card fields on web

#### **EDUCATION**

# **AWS Certified Cloud Architect**

2022

B.S. in Material Science Engineering University of California - Irvine Irvine, CA